"妙警贼探" 前情提要...
Previously on White Collar...
Mosconi法典
The Mosconi Codex.
这可不是一般的书
This is no ordinary book.
我觉得Hagen在利用你
I think Hagen is using you.
率先破解出法典是我们
The only chance we have of getting a leg up on him
扳倒他的唯一机会
is by deciphering the Codex first.
- Neal开小差了 对吧?  - 没错 他开小差了
- Neal took off, didn't he?  - Yeah, he sure did.
找下他去了哪儿
Find out where he went.
离那个伏特加酒吧一个街区的监控像头
Surveillance cameras a block from the vodka room
拍到了一个的哥
led us to a cabbie.
会有什么吸引他过来的原因吗?
Is there any reason he'd slip away to come here?
Neal来一定是有原因的
Neal always has a reason.
你没事吧?
You okay?
直到晚上听到你回家
I can't exhale until I hear you
我才可以松一口气
walk through that door at night.
Siegel探员被人谋杀
Agent Siegel's murder
是一次随机的暴力行动
was a random act of violence.
但不会发生在我身上
But it's not gonna happen to me.
我保证
I promise.
但法典一直以来
But the Codex has been hidden away
都被藏起来
its entire existence.
你怎么弄到副本的?
How did you get a copy?
我们的法典副本是不完整的
Our copy of the codex is incomplete.
你手头有多少?
How much do you have?
只有一章
A single chapter.
第13章
It's Chapter 13.
他所写的所有书中
In all the books he ever produced,
从没出现过第13章
he never wrote a Chapter 13.
新发型 新西装
Haircut, new suit.
今天是什么日子?
What's the occasion?
就在这天
On this very day,
我走进了市中心的一个画廊
I walked into a downtown art gallery
一眼看见了我未来的妻子
and first laid eyes on my future wife.
噢 例行的艺术犯罪案
Ah, routine art crime investigation
变成了你生命中最幸运的一天
turns into the luckiest day of your life.
对啊
I agree.
为了庆祝
And to celebrate,
我们打算去第一次约会的
we're going to the same restaurant
那家餐厅
we went to on our first date.
Papaya King餐厅吗?
Papaya King?
是La Cucina De Tua Nonna餐厅
La Cucina De Tua Nonna.
红酱 秸秆瓶葡萄酒
Red sauce, wine in straw bottles.
餐巾有塞进领子吗?
Napkin tucked into your collar?
我特别记得所有的纪念日
I'm making it a point to remember all the anniversaries.
生日 婚礼
Birthdays, weddings,
从饲养师那买Satchmo回家的那天
the day we brought Satchmo home from the breeders.
以为是白鹳叼它去你家的
I imagined a stork delivery.
- 是12月7日  - 珍珠港被偷袭那天?
- December 7th.  - Pearl harbor day?
另一个引以为耻的纪念日是
Another day that will live in infamy.
我第一次抓到你那天
First time I arrested you.
嗯 四年之后 我们又重新示范了一次
Hmm, and four years later we did it all over again.
- 对  - 但是这次
- Yeah.  - But this time,
- 你送我脚链了  - 对了
- You gave me jewelry.  - Oh.
所以我叫你来
Which is why I asked you to meet me here.
上次在伏特加酒吧的秘密行动
I removed your anklet
我去掉你的脚铐
for our undercover operation at the vodka room.
不久 我就发现这了
Soon after, I found this.
办公室里不是有无数支这样的笔吗?
Don't we have hundreds of those back at the office?
我觉得这支有特殊意义
I wonder this has special significance
第56街的办公楼 Brivege Coral诊所
Office building, 56 streets, Brivege Coral practic.
我们的下个案子吗?
Our next case?
可能是我一个人的
It could be mine.
我随叫随到
I am here to help.
你可以回家了
You can go home now.
这年头 别再点秸秆瓶葡萄酒了 试试桑娇维塞
This year, skip the straw bottle wine. Spring for some sangiovese.
我平常吃什么就点什么
I will order what I always order.
我下载到了手机上 这样就能一直看了
I downloaded it to my phone so I'd always have it with me.
我仍旧喜欢意大利菜
I still love Italian.
我仍旧爱你
I still love you.
你第一次做标志就是为我做的吗?
So am I the first guy you ever made a sign for?
那是第一个没有写"滚开"的标志
It was the first sign that didn't say "go away."
噢 那也不会阻挠我
Oh, it wouldn't have discouraged me.
你有没有想过如果那天没有走进我的画廊
Did you ever think where you would be
你现在会在哪里吗?
if you didn't walk into my gallery that day?
没有 从没想过
Nope. Never.
太可怕了 不敢想
Too scary to think about.
工作上的事怎样? 有进展吗?
How's work going? Getting any better?
有 我们把Siegel的照片挂在荣誉墙上了
Yeah, we added Siegel's picture to the honor wall.
那也算是进展吧
That was something, at least.
喂 这是在庆祝什么?
Hey, what kind of celebration is this?
- 都没酒了  - 谢谢
- Glasses are almost empty.  - Thank you.
- 打扰下  - 噢
- Scusi.  - Oh.
我们没点这些
We didn't order these.
怎么了? 你认识她吗?
What's wrong? Do you know her?
应该认识
I think I do.
那是Jill
That's Jill.
哪个Jill
Jill.
匡提科那个
From Quantico.
她就是Jill啊?
Oh, that's Jill?
对 我的前女友
Right. My ex-girlfriend.
- Peter 你好  - 你好
- Peter.  - Yes.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
20年没见了
20 years long.
没想到今晚在这见到你
I never thought I'd see you here, tonight.
我跟踪你来的
I hunted you down.
噢
Oh.
这是我妻子Elizabeth
This is my wife, Elizabeth.
很高兴认识你
It's great to meet you.
等下 我好像打断你们了
Uh, wait, I've interrupted something.
没有
Oh, no.
只是个平常的周二晚上 对吧?
This is just an average Tuesday night for us, right?
来 坐下 一起吧
Come on, sit down. Join us.
- 好啊  - 好吧
- Okay.  - Okay.
好啊
Okay.
那你在纽约做什么呢?
So, um, what are you doing in New York?
我在调查一个案子 就来找你
I'm on a case. I'd look you up.
你怎么找到我的?
How'd you find me?
找人是我的职业 Peter
That's what I do, Peter.
你还在SSG吗?
You still in SSG?
至少现在还是
Last time I checked in.
什么是SSG?
What's SSG?
SSG就是特别监督小组
SSG: special surveillance group.
我们追捕坏家伙 跟踪他们
We track down the bad guys, follow 'em,
记录下他们的惺忪
record 'em if we can.
听起来很牛
Sounds fascinating.
- 你还喝波旁威士忌吗?  - 偶尔吧
- You still drink bourbon?  - On occasion.
这种酒真是超级特别
Well, this is a damn special one.
你喝吗?
How about you?
好啊
Sure, why not?
记得我们怎么敬酒吗?
Remember our toast?
为了真理 正义...
Truth, justice...
别挡我们的路
And stay out of our way.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 伊娃 翠西打酱油 噹噹 爱鼠影 捞小盐
校对: 爱鼠影
妙警贼探 第五季第7集
这就是我家
Here it is.
每次经过这个房子
Every time I pass this house
我都忍不住想敲门 看看里面
I was tempted to knock and ask for a look inside.
你早该进来了
Oh, you should have.
我的女房东会邀请你进来喝咖啡的
My landlady would have invited you in for coffee.
天啊 就像终于读到一本梦寐以求的好书
God, it's like a good book I'm finally getting to read.
真不敢相信你住在这
I can't believe you live here.
我只是租了书的后记
Well, I just rent the epilogue.
我倒杯酒给你好吗?
Can I get you a glass of wine?
联邦调查局探员工作时可以喝酒吗?
FBI agents are allowed to drink on the job?
我们无时无刻都在工作
Well, we're always on the job.
有选择吗?
What choice do we have?
现在你加入我们了
And now that you're joining us,
我也要让你腐败下
I'm gonna corrupt you too.
- 谢谢  - 嗯
- Thank you.  - Mm hmm.
你们诡异的第13章在哪?
So where's this phantom Chapter 13 of yours?
在这
Right here.
不可能
It can't be.
为什么? 有问题吗?
Why? What's wrong?
这是真的 所以才有问题
What's wrong is that it's right.
这... 这... 这是Mosconi 但不可能的
It's... It... It's a Mosconi, but that's impossible.
这就是他创作的唯一第13章了
That would make it the only Chapter 13 that he ever made.
是从放在Gershon博物馆的法典上
Well, it was copied directly from the Codex
直接复制下来的
at the Gershon museum.
这可是他的笔迹
It is his handwriting.
太不可思议了
This is crazy.
还有这
And this.
这里
Here.
这是一幅画的草稿
It's a study for a painting
这本书发布一年后
That he didn't put on canvas
他才画到画布上
until a year after this was published.
所以这些页不可能是其它人伪造的
So these pages, they couldn't have been done by anyone else.
一定是他在纽约时创作的
And this has to be from his New York period.
1886年
1886.
他待在这的时间不超过一年
He was here less than a year.
联邦调查局的艺术犯罪案数据库显示的
FBI art crimes database.
可能他还在纽约写了这章唯一的第13章
Maybe he wrote his only chapter 13 in New York as well.
Mosconi匆匆回意大利了
Well, Mosconi rushed back to Italy in a hurry.
为什么匆匆离开还是一个谜
The why he ran is a mystery.
他留给我们这本书就更是一个谜了
And the book he left us is more of a what than a why.
他是个莫名其妙的人 喜欢拼图
He was a puzzling man who loved puzzles.
Mosconi相信如果一个人想要真相
See, Mosconi believed that if someone wanted the truth,
就应该去找
they should have to search for it.
你... 你在干什么?
What... what are you doing?
如果这本书是一个拼图 这些可能是拼块
If this book is a puzzle, maybe these are the pieces.
看
Look at that.
过来
Come here.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
这是一块
Here's one.
中间那块在哪?
Where's the middle?
肯定就在这里面
It's gotta be here somewhere.
不可思议
It's incredible.
看上去像一个彩色玻璃窗
It looks like a stained glass window.
但如果他是在纽约写第13章的
But if he wrote Chapter 13 when he was in New York,
这个彩色玻璃窗
this stained glass window
肯定就在曼哈顿
could be right here in Manhattan.
你... 你知道你刚做了什么吗?
Do you... do you realize what you've just done?
随便翻折了法典?
Made a mess of the Codex?
不 我... 我觉得你可能
No, I... I think you might have just made
找到了数十年来Mosconi研究
one of the most important discoveries
最重要的发现之一
on Mosconi in decades.
工作到深夜呢?
Ah, working into the night?
真不错
Impressive.
你该知道联邦调查局不赞成加班
You should know the FBI frowns on overtime.
我们... 我们有了惊人的进步 长官
Uh, We... we've made incredible progress, sir.
对
Yes.
Caffrey探员会告诉你进展的
I'm gonna let Agent Caffrey fill you in.
好的 我还要...
Sure. You know, I'm gonna...
调查这个窗
research this window.
看下能否找到地方
See if I can find out where it is.
好的 我也会利用联邦调查局的资源
Yeah, I'll put my FBI resources on it as well.
看下谁先找到
We can see who finds it first.
好
'Kay.
怎么了?
What?
你 工作 和女人... 罪恶的三角组合
You, business, and women... The unholy trinity.
Rebecca只是在做法典的事
Rebecca is all about the business of the Codex.
我以前没见识过吗
Oh, like I've never seen this before.
有Kate 有Alex 还有Sarah
Kate, Alex, Sarah.
现在轮到Rebecca了
Now Rebecca.
肯定不止研究法典这么简单
There's more behind this than the Codex.
你现在是爱情专家了对吧?
So you're an expert on romance now?
一个在恋爱上不智而过于深情的人
One who has loved not wisely, but too well.
奥赛罗(莎士比亚四大悲剧之一)
Othello.
是 我们都知道他结局如何
Yeah. We all know how that turned out.
你没事吧?
You okay?
回来的路上一句话都没说
Pretty quiet on the way home.
嗯 我不想打破咒语
Well, I didn't wanna break the spell.
听我说 亲爱的
Oh, look, honey.
Jill向我挑战
Jill challenged me.
你知道我去匡蒂科的时候
You know that I didn't enter Quantico
没那么自信的
all that sure of myself.
但是她竭尽全力胜过我
But she tried so hard to beat me
而我为了胜过她 也是用尽全力
That I worked my butt off to beat her.
- 然后...  - 看看你现在的成就
- And...  - Look at you now.
不是 我不是那个意思
No, that's not what I meant.
只是... 只是我从未想过
It's... It's just that I never thought
我会有今天的成就
that I could finish as high as I did.
你知道的
You know that.
我会有今天的成就 全是因为你
You're the reason I'm the man I am today.
接着说
Continue.
嗯
Hmm.
没有你 我去年不知道怎么熬过来
I couldn't have gotten through this past year without you.
也许... 年年都是如此
Or... any year.
不管怎样 今天是我们的纪念日啊
You know, it's still our anniversary.
我正希望你这样说呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
谢谢你 探长
Thank you, Detective.
是的 嗯 希望如此
Right, well, let's hope it does.
再见 交给我们吧
Bye. We'll take it from here.
纽约市警察局打来的
That was NYPD.
两天前有人在布鲁克林强占车辆
Two days ago someone in Brooklyn commandeered a vehicle
自称是联邦调查局的
Posing as an FBI agent.
昨天又发生了一起
Yesterday he struck again.
- 他出示证件了吗?  - 出示了
- Did he flash a badge?  - Mm-hmm.
纽约警察局不知道是真是假
NYPD doesn't know if it's real or not.
也许是Siegel的
Or if it could be Siegel's.
可能性不大
Chances are slight that it is,
但是我们也要查一下
but we need to check it out.
可能是两周来第一个有用的线索
Could be our first solid lead in two weeks.
我想让你和Jones去查
I want you and Jones on this.
我信任的两个
Two people I trust.
我信任的一个半吧
Well, 1 1/2.
那是谁?
Who is that?
啊 不重要
Uh, no one important.
找到线索 抓住这个人
Come up with something to catch this guy.
- 出去吧  - 你似乎很紧张
- Now go.  - You seem nervous.
出去吧 出去
Just leave, just leave.
嘿
Hey.
你是Neal Caffrey
Neal Caffrey.
我们认识吗?
Do we know each other?
我叫Jill Stone 我熬了一晚上
Jill Stone. I stayed up all night
看你俩的案件卷宗
reading the case files of you two.
想不看都不行
Couldn't put it down.
好东西让你好久难以入睡
The good ones keep you up at night.
没错 坏的让你更久难以入睡
Mm-hmm. The bad ones even longer.
他正要出去呢
He was just leaving.
没想到你会来
I wasn't expecting you.
我们比较神秘
We're a secretive bunch.
别告诉我咱俩看到的不一样
Tell me we're looking at the same thing.
Peter Burke有些不安
Peter Burke uncomfortable.
那不是他的正常状态
That's not his natural state.
你知道她是联邦调查局的吗?
You know she's FBI?
嗯 穿的不是一般般的西装
Well, it's not your run of the mill suit.
不知道她平时穿什么
Not that she ever wears one.
看她的举止
Look at the way she holds herself.
锋芒毕露
Open. Totally exposed.
非常有自信
Confidence and plenty of it.
喔 她那样摸他
Ooh. Oh, that's not the first time
已经不是第一次了
She's touched him like that.
- 嗯嗯  - 他们有段情史
- Uh-uh.  - They have a past.
看她的眼睛 一直注视着他
Look at her eyes. All over his face.
嗯 她想知道他对她还有没有感觉
Yeah, she wants to see if he still feels anything.
嗯嗯
Uh-huh.
- 喔  - 怎么了?
- Whoa.  - Whoa what?
- 他们上过床  - Peter吗?
- They slept together.  - Peter?
不是最近的事
Not recently.
好吧 我听说
All right, you know I heard
他在匡蒂科的时候
he had a pretty serious relationship
跟一个女探员认真交往过
with a female agent down at Quantico.
后来她加入了SSG
She joined SSG.
联邦调查局的中央情报局吗?
The CIA of the FBI?
那些是很牛逼的探员
Those are some badass agents.
怪不得这么有自信
That explains the confidence.
那是Peter的前女友
That's Peter's ex.
一定是
It has to be.
我不能在你妻子面前跟你谈案件的事
I couldn't talk about the case in front of your wife.
跟精英调查小组有关的吗?
White Collar related?
我在查一个叫Mason Sadowski的科学怪才
I'm tracking a tech genius named Mason Sadowski.
不怎么吓人啊
Doesn't look all that intimidating.
但在当今社会 这种人最麻烦
In today's world that's what trouble looks like.
他是一个团队的成员
He's part of a team that invented
这个团队为我们的一位高层国防承包商
a new and extremely dangerous microchip
新发明了一种极度危险的微型芯片
for one of our top defense contractors.
然后他变卦了吗?
Then he decided he didn't wanna share?
是的
Exactly.
这芯片一定非常重要
Must be a very important chip.
跟破解密码有关
Something to do with decoding passwords.
有了它 就连三脚猫的黑客都可以破解
With it, a two-bit hacker could break through
我们最复杂强大的安全墙
our most sophisticated security walls.
我们的敌人最想得到的
Low-hanging fruit for our enemies.
是的 他把东西放到了黑市上
Yeah, he put it on the black market.
我已经建立了一个假身份 伊朗的经纪人
I've established a cover I.D. as a broker for Iran.
下了饵了吗?
Set the hook yet?
- 他已经上钩了  - 很好
- He swallowed it.  - Good.
等着交易的时候抓住他
Waiting for a buy time to reel him in.
我的问题是:
My problem: most buyers
大部分买主是两个人代表外国集团
representing foreign interests come in twos.
按照行规 我需要一个帮手
In order for the ruse to work, I need a partner.
有卧底经验的
Someone with undercover experience.
你又信得过的人
Someone you can trust.
在纽约 你最合适
More than any other agent in New York.
头儿Bruce Hawes已经批准了
Section chief Bruce Hawes put the order through personally.
哦 Bruce啊?
Oh, Bruce, huh?
不只是Bruce
Not only Bruce.
你的名声在华盛顿也响当当
Your name gets dropped a lot in Washington.
听上去不错
Nice to hear.
你熟悉纽约 我不熟悉
You know New York, and I don't have GPS.
另外除了我 你是最好的
Besides, you're the best. Next to me, of course.
哦 那是在匡提科 现在是现在
Oh, that was Quantico. This is now.
我会安排好交易
I'll set up the buy.
好戏上场了
This is gonna be fun.
明白了
Got that too. Here.
- 很高兴见到你  - 保重
- Good to see you.  - Take care.
拜
Bye.
她令Peter浮想联翩啊
She left Peter with a lot to think about.
没错
Uh-huh.
回去工作!
Get back to work!
而且还是很紧张
And still uncomfortable.
- 噢 嘿 你的计划要推后了  - 为什么?
- Oh, hey, you got plans later?  - Why?
特别探员主管让咱们去执行另一个任务
ASAC gave us an assignment.
纽约警察局通知Peter
NYPD informed Peter
有人在布鲁克林用了Siegel的证件
someone may be using Siegel's badge in Brooklyn.
好的 我会联系纽约警察局
All right, I'll coordinate with NYPD.
我们需要罪犯的资料和他的外贸特点
We'll need the perp's description and his m.o.
才能知道我们要找的是谁
So we know what we're looking for.
或许想办法让他找到我们
Or we help him find us.
Jill只是需要我帮忙的联邦调查局探员
Jill's just an FBI agent who needs help on a case.
就这些 没了
That's it. End of story.
你从来不会用那种眼神看Jones
You never look at Jones like that.
- 够了  - 等一下
- Drop it.  - Hold on a second.
El知道你前女友是你的新搭档吗?
Does El know that your old ex is your new partner?
待时机成熟 今晚我就会告诉她
I'm gonna tell her tonight when it's more relaxed.
好吧 至少告诉我细节
All right, at least give up the details.
你俩是怎么分手的?
What broke you two lovers up?
我也不知道
I don't know.
道不同不相为谋吧
She went west, I went east.
这已经不重要了
It doesn't matter anymore.
- 这当然重要了 - 不 重要的是...
- It always matters.  - No, what matters...
你得抓到那个盗用证件的家伙
is that you catch the guy flashing the badge.
好吧 今晚我和Jones就扮成羊
All right, Jones and I are gonna cruise Brooklyn tonight
去布鲁克林 但是...
in sheep's clothing, but...
但是什么?
But what?
狼也要找肥硕的羊
The wolves need a sleeker wardrobe.
好吧
Yes.
先送我回家
Drop me off.
晚饭快好了
Dinner's almost ready.
嗯
Mm.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
Jill今天来我办公室了
Jill came to my office today.
我猜到了她早晚会去
I figured she would.
为什么不给我倒杯葡萄酒
Why don't you pour me a glass of wine
告诉我你们谈了点什么?
and tell me all about it?
这种葡萄酒?
What kind of wine is this?
噢 那是去年圣诞节Mozzie给咱们的
Oh, that's the bottle Mozzie gave us last Christmas
- 你当时还不敢打开  - 现在我也不敢
- you were afraid to open.  - Still am.
- 你请客人来家了?  - 没有
- You expecting someone?  - No.
噢... 嗨 Elizabeth
Oh... Hi, Elizabeth.
哇 闻上去像是在意大利菜
Um, wow, it smells like Italy in here.
我都忘了现在还有人会做饭
I forgot people still make dinner.
我忘了还有人不请自来
I forgot people just drop by.
真不好意思打扰你们了
I'm so sorry I keep interrupting you.
我应该先打电话的 但是我们现在有要紧的事儿
I should have called first, but we're just kind of in a rush.
- "我们"?  - 哦 Peter
- "we"?  - Oh, Peter.
我知道他们藏在哪儿了
I found where the guy's holed up,
所以现在我们要去调查下
so we gotta do recon on the thing now, right now.
你们现在一起工作?
You guys workin' on a case together?
这就是Jill来纽约的原因
That's why Jill is in New York
因为案子属于精英调查小组...
and since it was White Collar related...
- 什么案子?  - 是机密
- What's it about?  - Mm, it's classified.
好吧 我们只在这所房子里讨论
Oh, well, nothing we discuss ever leaves this house.
对不起 亲爱的
I'm sorry, hon.
我们不能透露这个
We can't discuss this one.
- 你还好吧?  - 我为什么不好?
- You okay?  - Why wouldn't I be?
回家的路上我打给你
I'll call you on my way home.
我会让他安全回家的
I'll try to get him home in one piece.
好吧
Yeah.
你住在车里?
Do you live in this?
有时是必须的
When I have to.
车里少了个冰箱和电炉
All you're missing is a fridge and a hot plate.
是吧 我正准备放进来
Well, I'm thinking about putting in
- 还有有壁炉和浴缸  - 不错
- A fireplace and Jacuzzi.  - That'd be nice.
你怎么还在出外勤?
How come you're still in the field?
我是说 过去你可是很有野心的
I mean, you had big ambitions way back then.
我还以为你已经是副局长了
I expected you to be assistant director by now.
我有机会去华盛顿了
I'm on a Washington track.
所以这段时间 我身兼双职
For the time being, I'm serving double duty.
特别探员主管和Neal的负责人
ASAC and Neal's handler.
我做得很开心
I'm pretty happy doing both.
- Peter...  - 怎么了?
- Peter...  - What?
你不用在我面前逞强
You don't have to put up a strong front for me.
你曾经是一名探员的上司 结果他被杀了
You were the supervisor of an agent who got killed.
我知道你很受伤
I know you're hurting.
大家都是
The entire bureau is.
是啊
Yeah.
这段记忆很难抹去
It's been hard to shake it.
八年前我失去了我的搭档
I lost my partner eight years ago.
现在还忘不了
Still can't.
坐在好车里追捕犯人
Cruisin' for the bad guy in a sweet ride,
- 跟Crockett和Tubbs一样  - 没错
- just like Crockett and Tubbs.  - Ah.
现在真是身处梦中
I am living the dream.
你难道是根据"迈阿密风云"规划的未来?
Did you base your entire future on Miami Vice?
希尔街的布鲁斯 警花拍档...
Ah, Hill Street Blues, Cagney & Lacey...
所有关于警察的电视剧
any show about law enforcement.
我的观点截然不同
I had a different perspective.
我来猜猜 赞助坏蛋吗?
Let me guess, rooting for the bad guys?
只会在他们善良时帮他们 Cagney
Only when they were good, Cagney.
我们已经兜风了三个小时
We've been driving around for about three hours.
这家伙在哪儿?
Where is this guy?
我们当时在追捕在Pomona抢劫银行的一对夫妻
We were chasing a couple that robbed a bank in Pomona.
他们分头逃跑了 我追那个男人
They split up. I followed the guy.
Earl去追那个女的 她假装投降
Earl was following the girl. She pretended to surrender.
向他开了枪
She shot him.
所以你现在都单独办案?
Is that why you work alone?
虽然并不是我的错 但感觉还是我的责任
It wasn't my fault, but it still feels like it was.
Siegel原本会来我的办公室
Siegel used to come to my office
就只是想听我讲以前办的案子
and just wanna hear about my old cases.
他总是听不够
He couldn't get enough.
我把他从芝加哥调过来
I brought him here from Chicago.
保护David是我的责任
David was my responsibility.
保护不了所有人
Can't protect everybody.
没错
No.
还没法替代他们的位置
And you can't take their place.
哪怕有时候你非常想这么做
Even though sometimes you wish you could.
对
Mm.
找到凶手了吗?
Any closer to finding the killer?
还没有
Not yet.
但今天有了条线索
Today we got a potential lead.
你会抓到凶手的
You'll find him.
正义并非一直会来得那么快
Justice is not always as swift as we want it to be.
那是我们要找的人吗?
Isn't that our guy?
没错 他出来了 我们的机会来了
Yeah, he's out of his room. Now's our chance.
- 怎么了?  - 我也不知道
- What?  - I don't know.
感觉不太妙
Bad feeling.
希望我们别在犯人出现前就被劫了
I hope we don't get jacked before our perp shows up.
等等
Hold on a second.
等等 你在做什么?
Whoa, what are you doing?
你知道Peter不喜欢别人碰他的按钮的
You know Peter doesn't like folks touching his buttons.
只是想换个好点的视野
Trying to get a better view.
看来你的期待要成真了
Looks like your hope is about to come true.
- 看你左边  - 是吗?
- On your left.  - Yeah?
我需要征用你们的车
I need your car.
- 联邦调查局在办案  - 好的
- Official FBI business.  - Yep.
快点下车! 罪犯要逃走了
Get out now! Criminal's getting away.
- 冷静点 伙计!  - 我们要怎样
- Chill, man!  - How are we
领回这辆车?
gonna get our car back?
真的联邦调查局
Real FBI.
把手放在车顶上
Hands on the roof.
怎么样?
What do you got?
如果我没穿高跟鞋 肯定能追上你
I would have had you if I wore flats.
以前可没见你找借口过
Well, I never knew you to make excuses before.
好吧 这次算你赢了
Okay, you won that one.
好好品味 因为这会是最后一次
Savor it, because it'll be your last.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢你让我们进来 新婚蜜月
Thanks for letting us in. Honeymooners, right?
总会忘拿些东西
Always forgetting something.
没关系 先生
Si, senor.
好了 我们找块地方藏枪
Come on, let's find a place to stash the gun
以免他在交易前搜我们的身
in case we get patted down before the buy.
你觉得他随身带着芯片吗?
You think he took the chip with him?
如果我这么认为 早就在外面逮捕他了
If I thought so, I would have taken him outside.
也许他藏在了这儿
Then maybe he left it here.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
我们离开匡蒂科的时候
You could have had any assignment you wanted
你哪儿都能去
when we left Quantico.
为什么选了洛杉矶?
Why Los Angeles?
那辆车看着很眼熟
Hey, that looks familiar.
没错
Yeah.
跟我们进去时遇到的一样
Same guys we passed on our way in.
他们也许也是来买芯片的竞争者
They might be competitive shoppers for our chip.
我们看看他们是谁
Let's find out who they are.
假装是在约会的情侣 拍张自拍
Take a selfie like we're a couple on a date.
好了 再近点
Come on, closer.
得装得像些
We gotta sell it.
Neal 抓到了吗?
Neal, you got him?
你把流血不止的他留在了人行道上
You left him bleeding on the sidewalk.
胸部中弹
A bullet in his chest.
- 他是个联邦调查局探员  - 跟我们一样
- An FBI agent.  - One of us.
我没杀那家伙
I didn't kill the dude.
我拿了他的证件 把枪丢进了垃圾桶
I pulled that badge and gun outta the trash.
我发誓
I swear.
要知道 杀人犯发誓的时候
You know, when a murderer swears,
我总不会相信他们的
I tend not to believe them.
那是个星期五
It was a Friday.
大概一个月前 人们去存政府补贴支票的时候
About a month ago. When people cash their g-checks.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
几点钟?
What time of day was it?
挺晚了 天快黑了
Later. Almost dark.
之前你在哪儿? 三点到四点的时候
Where were you before that? Between 3:00 and 4:00 p.m.?
我... 我不记得了
I... I don't remember.
"不记得了" 知道吗?
"I don't remember". Well, you know what?
因为你拿了证件 还拿了枪
It doesn't matter because you've got the badge
所以也无所谓了
and you've got the gun.
上面都是你的指纹
And your prints are all over them.
你肯定会坐牢的
You're going down for this.
我们走吧
Let's go.
- 我很期待  - 不 等等
- My skin is starting to crawl.  - No, wait, wait.
那家伙被杀的时候 我在Dante酒铺里
When your guy got hit, I was inside Dante's Liquor.
待了一个小时?
For an hour?
想等人走光了 再抢一票
Waited till it emptied out so I could rob it.
存支票那天 酒铺总会有很多人 现金也多
The place was crowded and full of cash on check day.
听着 你们可以去查
Look, check it out.
那家店有监控录像 这可做不了假
The store's got cameras. They don't lie.
进去盯着他
Get in there with him.
快点去酒铺 我要看监控录像
Head down to the liquor store. I wanna see that footage.
好的
Yeah.
听着 你已经让他坦白了
Look, you got him to talk.
嘿 Peter
Peter.
你已经尽力了
You did everything you could.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
你还没睡?
You're awake?
我一直都会等你的
I always wait up for you.
有时候你也会睡着
Well, sometimes you fall asleep.
但这次没有
Not this time.
都告诉我吧
Tell me all about it.
这是机密
It's classified.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
Jill又不会发现的
It's not like jill will ever find out.
我不能说
I can't.
我们一直都讨论你在查的案子的
We always discuss your cases.
我知道 但... 我也很想告诉你
I know, but I... And I can't wait to tell you about it.
但... 得等案子结束了
But... not until it's done.
这个案子有什么特别的?
What's so special about this one?
抱歉 这...
I'm sorry, it's...
是机密
Classified.
你明白的 对吧?
You understand, right?
我当然明白
Of course I do.
我可是警嫂
I'm an FBI wife.
面部识别系统
Facial recognition scan
辨认出他们是Eric Healey和Robert Bly
fegged them as Eric Healey and Robert Bly.
都是前秘密组织成员
They're both ex-black ops.
他们现在是自由职业
They've been freelancing
为我们不太熟悉的国防承包商工作
for some of our lesser known defense contractors.
他们是高级雇佣兵
They're high-end mercenaries.
没错 看起来我们并不是唯一
Yeah, it does look like we're not the only ones
在找这个天才的人
hunting our genius.
对手国防承包商
Rival defense contractors
会不择手段想弄到芯片
would do anything for that technology.
我觉得这些家伙想成为新卖家
I think these guys are looking to be the new sellers.
这就意味着他们不会买芯片
Which means they're not gonna buy it.
而回去偷
They're gonna steal it.
嘿 Elizabeth Burke
Hey, Elizabeth Burke.
用棕色袋子装的爱心礼物
Bearing gifts in a brown paper bag.
想想就羡慕
I can only imagine.
这只是他的午餐
Oh, it's just his lunch.
他早上忘带了
He forgot it this morning.
你怎么没参加?
Why aren't you in there?
他们觉得我没必要知道
Uh, scratched off the need to know list.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
来吧 我们一起进去
Come on, let's go in.
不了 Neal 我不是那种多疑的妻子
No, Neal, I'm not that kind of wife.
我绝对就是那种线人
Well, I'm definitely that kind of C.I.
不用了 我就把东西放在他桌上了
No, I'll just leave it on his desk.
好吧
All right.
你觉得这个Jill怎么样?
What do we think of this Jill?
还需要再观察观察
There's need for further study.
我觉得她很孤独
I think she's lonely.
她住在一辆86年的雪佛兰里
Well, she lives out of an '86 chevy.
我觉得她不会参加很多晚宴
I doubt she throws a lot of dinner parties.
从没结过婚
She never got married.
Peter可能是他爱过的最后一个男人
Peter could be the last man she ever loved.
没移情别恋的话 20年可是很长一段时间
20 years is a long time to go without loving someone else.
你爱上了Peter... 就会一直爱他
You fall in love with Peter, you... you are in love.
我很难想象这份感情会消失
I can't imagine those feelings ever going away.
至少不会完全消失
Not completely.
真的?
Really?
你说Peter Burke? 就是会议室那个男人?
Peter Burke? The man in the conference room?
你无从知道
You have no idea.
这很好
This is good.
我会让Jones和纽约警局合作
We'll have Jones coordinate with NYPD.
就能弄到这辆SUV现在的位置
We'll get a current location of the SUV.
追踪这辆车 就能知道它的实时位置
He can trail it and give us updates of its whereabouts.
不 Peter 我想我说得很清楚了
No. Peter. I think I was pretty clear.
不能让别人知道 谁都不能参与
No one else can know anything. No one else can be involved.
这是我的案子 就得按我的规矩办
It's my case, my rules.
这是我们的案子
It's our case.
是我让你入伙的
I brought you in on this.
别逼我把你撤出去
Don't make me take you off.
你把案子带给了精英调查小组
You brought it to White Collar,
而我是特别探员主管
and I'm ASAC here.
用我们的办法 否则你就别办这个案子了
We'll do it our way or you're out.
你是开玩笑吧
You're not serious.
难道我这表情看着像在开玩笑?
This face doesn't look serious to you?
好吧... 主管先生
Okay... ASAC.
Jones会追查这辆车 直接向我们报告
Jones keeps tabs, he reports back to us,
但我们不用告诉他原因
but we don't tell him why.
同意
Agreed.
这个
Yeah.
我要和El打个招呼
I'm gonna say hi to El.
好的
Yep.
你打电话给她了吗?
Did you call her?
打了 El态度还是很好
I did. El couldn't have been sweeter.
- 那还不错 对吧?  - 糟透了
- That's good, right?  - It's terrible.
她生我气的时候
When she's upset with me,
总会让自己很迷人 行程很满
she makes herself irresistible and unavailable.
- 这方法很好  - 快把我逼疯了
- Oh, nice technique.  - Drives me crazy.
好吧 赶快回家 当面谈谈
All right, go home, talk to her in person.
我不能
I can't.
Jill在安排交易
Jill's setting something up.
如果我跟El道歉到一半 跑去见Jill...
If I have to leave El mid-apology to meet Jill...
那就派别的探员去和Jill合作
So just assign a different agent to work with Jill.
这案子太重要了
This case is too important.
再说了 除我以外她不信任任何人
Besides, she doesn't trust anyone else.
好吧
Okay.
案子和Jill 到底哪个才是重点?
Is it about the case or is it about Jill?
我可以无所顾忌地跟Jill谈David的死
I can talk to Jill about losing David.
她自己也是过来的人了
She's been through it herself.
但El已经够提心吊胆的了 你不想再刺激她
And you don't wanna worry El any more than she already is.
没错
I don't.
这一年来她受得够多了
She's been through enough this year.
多到让她相信没有什么坏事是绝对不可能的
Enough to believe that other bad things are possible.
El知道我爱她
El knows that I'm in love with her.
- 她信任我  - 信任?
- She trusts me.  - Trust?
可你看 你反倒不信任她了
Now you see it, now you don't.
我得走了
I have to go.
那件不能提的案子?
Thing I can't talk about?
有眉目了
It's going down.
- 你必须跟踪他  - 听着 我绝不会去跟踪他
- You must follow him.  - Look, I am not following him.
我绝不会跟踪自己的丈夫
I'm not following my husband.
他从来没让我感到不信任他
He's never given me reason not to trust him.
- 到此为止  - Mozzie
- Until now.  - Mozzie.
你大可以信任
You can trust truffles
佩里戈尔地区产的块菌
harvested in the Perigord region,
马德拉的手织枕套
bed linens handwoven in Madeira,
甚至一只名叫莫扎特的泰迪熊
and, for the most part, a teddy bear named Mozart.
但人心? 几乎没有绝对的信任
But people? Almost never.
你就信任Neal
You trust Neal.
就是因为有Neal
Neal is the reason
"没有"前面才放了个"几乎"
"never" was preceded by "almost".
反正我不去跟踪Peter
I'm not following Peter.
- 你必须得去  - 就不
- You must.  - I won't.
- 必须的  - 不
- You must.  - No.
那就跟踪那个女人
Then follow the woman.
还是说你对猫咪探长海枯石烂的信任也转移到她身上了?
Or does your intrepid faith in the suit extend to her as well?
- 查出什么了?  - 诶 Peter
- What do you have?  - Yeah, Peter.
我跟着那辆SUV到了村庄
I followed the SUV to the village.
他们停下车就去了一家餐厅
They just parked and went into a restaurant.
谢了 Jones 他们走的时候告诉我
Thanks, Jones. Let me know when they leave.
没问题
Okay.
那些佣兵刚进了家餐厅
Mercenaries just went into a restaurant.
咱们做完交易之前 他们应该还没吃完
That meal should keep 'em on the shelf until we make the buy.
既然他们是冲着芯片来的
Well, they're after the chip.
怎么还有闲情逸致吃饭?
Why stop for a meal?
他们又不知道咱们现在进行交易
They don't know our buy's going down now.
就连坏人也是要吃饭的嘛
Even bad guys gotta eat.
你跟你老婆还好吧?
You and the missus okay?
我看她离开办公室的时候行色匆匆的
She left the office in kind of a hurry.
挺好的 她就是路过帮我带个三明治
Yeah, she was just dropping by a sandwich.
真幸福
Sweet.
我还得靠快递小哥养活着
I depend on the kindness of delivery guys.
你没结过婚?
You never got married?
有谁能容忍我的性子?
Who would put up with me?
- 喂?  - 喂 Peter
- Yeah?  - Yeah, Peter.
我感觉事情不太对
I've got a bad feeling about this.
我们后门没安排人
We don't have eyes on the rear.
申请许可进行盘查
Requesting permission for a walk-through.
他连简单盘查一下也不行吗?
Can't he just do a simple walk-through?
说好的不行
It's not part of the agreement.
你叫他等着
You tell him to stand by.
别去了
Don't go.
她不想让我去 你想
She doesn't want me to go. You do.
- 没错  - 明白
- Right.  - Gotcha.
- 我去看看  - 明白
- I'm going in.  - Got it.
本来是Mozzie帮我的 但...
Mozzie was supposed to help me, but...
拇囊炎移除
Bunion removal.
- 我都听说了  - 好
- I heard all about it.  - Okay.
我觉得她住这儿
This is where I think she's staying.
我想让你陪我去
I want you to come with me.
我听说她住在她的86款雪佛兰卡普里斯里
I hear she stays at the '86 Caprice.
我看到一张他俩站在这家旅馆前的照片
I saw a picture of them in front of this hotel.
站得很近 非常近
Close. Extremely close.
她一脸的甜蜜
And she looked smitten,
但他一副想回家的样子
but he looked like he wanted to go home.
因为他爱的是你
Because he's in love with you.
这我知道 但我想知道的是
I know that. What I don't know
她到底什么目的
is her intentions with him.
他不是一般人 但他还是个男人
I mean, he's not an ordinary man, but he is a man.
他们去那肯定是为了案子
If they are there, it's for the case
所以此行会很危险
and that could be dangerous.
所以我要你陪我
That's why I need you.
你要是不去 我就一个人去
If you don't go with me, I'm gonna go alone.
等等
Wait.
我开车送你 你火气太大了
I'll drive. You're too angry.
坐着无所事事 咱们走吧
I'm tired of sitting. Let's go.
还早呢
We're early.
抓他个措手不及
We'll catch him off guard.
也有可能露馅
Or tip him off.
Peter 我又不是菜鸟
I've done this before, Peter.
听着 他们都未必在这里
Look, they're probably not even here.
好吧 他们出现了
Okay, they're here.
不是你想的样子
That is not what it looked like.
最好不是
It better not be.
你知道吗...
You know...
我一度真的以为会看到他俩
I really thought I was gonna see both of them
坐在板凳上如胶似漆 动手动脚的
sitting on stools so close to each other they were touching.
Peter举着一杯啤酒
You know, Peter having a beer
Jill端着那种
and Jill having whatever women have
女人勾引别人老公时会喝的酒
when they're sitting with someone else's husband.
别太急着下结论
All right, don't jump to conclusions.
晚了 我已经下了
Too late. Already jumped.
在吧台等着 我跟前台
Wait at the bar. I'll pull a room number
把房间号套出来
out of the desk clerk.
如果... 有房间号这一说的话
If... there is a room number.
那几个佣兵不见了
Mercenaries are gone.
他们肯定认出我们了
They must have I.D.'d us
就从餐厅后面开溜了
and snuck out the back of the restaurant.
让特警待命
I want you to put the tac team on alert.
我给Peter打电话
I'm calling Peter.
SSG的规矩
SSG procedure.
手机静音
Radio silence.
好吧 从现在开始追踪Peter的手机
Okay, start tracking Peter's cell phone now.
他可能中计了
He might be walking into an ambush.
- 喂 Elizabeth  - 喂 Neal
- Elizabeth.  - Neal.
一个Peter档案里的男子就在吧台
A man from Peter's file is in the bar.
他们来这就是为了他 的确是个案子
That's why they're here. It was the case.
我跟你说不要急着下结论的
I told you not to jump.
Peter肯定在找他
I'm sure Peter's looking for him.
我觉得我能拖住他
I think I could stall him.
帮我联系到Peter 好吗?
Call Peter for me, okay?
Elizabeth 别轻举妄动...
Elizabeth, don't do anything...
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
呃 你住在这家宾馆吗?
Um, are you staying at the hotel?
我 呃... 是的
I'm, uh... Yeah.
是的 我住在这 你呢?
Yeah, uh, I'm staying. You?
不是 只是进来喝一杯
No. Just getting a drink.
你有急事吗?
Are you in a rush?
什么?
What?
跟我坐会儿
Well, sit with me.
喝一杯
Have a drink.
呃... 过会儿行吗?
Um... maybe later?
现在不行吗?
Why not now?
我要开个会
I have a meeting.
呃 你把手机给我
Um, how about you give me your phone
我把号码留给你
and I'll give you my number
你半小时后打给我如何?
and you call me in a 1/2 hour?
好啊
Okay.
女士 您的账单
Ma'am, your check.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
Thanks.
- 好了  - 谢了
- All right.  - Thanks.
- 记得打过来噢?  - 一定
- Promise to call?  - Promise.
Neal 就是他 你联系上Peter了吗?
Neal, that's him. Did you get a hold of Peter?
没有 转到语音信箱了
No. Voicemail.
在这等着
Wait here.
我看看他们去哪
I need to see where they're going.
不 我也来
Oh, no, I'm coming.
跟我说说刚才都发生了什么
All right, tell me everything that happened.
好 我跟他调情
Well, um, okay, I flirted with him.
他也试着回应 但明显疏于此道
He tried to flirt back, but he was not very good at it.
- 接着说  - 他好像急着要走
- Keep going.  - He seemed anxious to leave.
他说要不30分钟之后见
He said maybe meet up in 30 minutes
然后就在我手机里留下了他的号码
and he put his number in my phone.
他把号码输进了你的手机?
He put his number in your phone?
让我看看
Let me see it.
那是什么?
What is that?
一款新的微芯片吧
Some kind of new microchip.
Peter只跟我说是有关信息安全的
All Peter told me was that it's about security.
咱们似乎找到了他俩正在找的东西
I think we found what he and Jill are looking for.
他不应该在等咱们来的吗?
Shouldn't he be waiting for us?
如你所说 咱们来早了
Like you said, we're early.
他按兵不动
He's playing it cool.
老婆 我跟你说了 咱们走错房间了
Honey, I told you, it's the wrong room.
嘿 我那天看见你们俩了
Hey, I saw you the other day.
拍我们的... 照片
Taking pictures... of us.
我们是度蜜月的
We're honeymooners.
我们以为这是我们的房间 但钥匙打不开
We thought this was our room, but our key doesn't work,
所以看来不是了
So I guess it isn't.
这边尽头只有这一间房
There's only one room on this end.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
我们... 我们可不想惹麻烦
We don't... we don't want any trouble.
我们这就走 行吗?
We'll just be leaving, all right?
包里装的什么?
What's in the bag?
没什么
Nothing.
衣服
Clothes.
打开来
Open it.
打开 不然让你把蜜月度成寡妇月
Open it, or you go from honeymooner to widow.
钞票说明你们俩
Buyers or feds.
要么是买家 要么是探员
Cash says that you're either one or the other.
还有第三种
Third option.
我们不过是一对
We're newlyweds
不喜欢用信用卡的新婚夫妇
who don't believe in credit cards.
他是很传统的那种
He's an old-fashioned kind of guy.
没错
That I am.
我... 我不知道他是谁
I... I don't know who he is,
但她是个买家
but she's a buyer.
交易本应今天完成的
The deal was supposed to go down today.
就现在
Right now.
芯片呢!
The chip!
我藏在楼下一个女人那里了
I hid it on a woman downstairs.
什么女人?
What woman?
等等 我们都是买家
Wait. We're both buyers.
我代表伊朗那边
Iranian interests.
至少今早还是的
Well, at least I was until this morning.
朝鲜打来电话
North Korea came calling.
还没出停车库我们的合作关系就破裂了
Our partnership wasn't gonna make it past the parking garage.
妈的
Son of a bitch.
如果你们两位可以加入我们团队
Their country would be very grateful
朝鲜那边会非常感激
if the two of you joined our team.
感激不尽
Extremely grateful.
听着 杀了他们俩
Look, kill the both of them.
你们尽管把钱拿走
You can take the money.
我把我的那一半分给你们
I'll cut you in on my half of the chip.
给我松绑就好
Just untie me.
好吧 你去楼下
All right, you have to go downstairs.
我手里有芯片
I have the chip.
我要进去
I'm going in.
给我 我进去
Give it to me. I'll take it in.
你是准备帮我进去呢
Are you gonna help me get in there,
还是得我自己敲门?
or am I gonna have to knock?
咱们好好谈谈
Let's discuss this.
我不知道你们为谁工作
I don't know who you're working for
也不知道他们给你们待遇如何
or what they're paying you,
但朝鲜一定会待你们更加优厚
but the North Koreans will beat it.
得了吧 他们连自己人都还喂不饱
They can't even feed their own people.
闭嘴吧你
Shut up.
你到底在找什么呢 新郎官?
What are you looking for, newlywed?
好吧
All right.
- 你什么都没看到  - 那是什么?
- You never saw this.  - What is that?
是我和Mozzie研制的
It's something Mozzie and I made.
现在进去吧 假装这里是你的房间
Now go in there like you own the place.
把芯片给他们看 但别拿得太近
Show them the chip, but keep it away from them.
帮我争取30秒
Okay, try to buy me 30 seconds.
小心
Careful.
我问你话呢 新郎官
I asked you a question, newlywed.
你们要的东西在我这
I've got what you want.
亲爱的 快离开这
Hon, get out of here now.
就... 就是她
Th... that's her.
我就是把芯片藏在她这的
That's the woman I stashed the chip on.
没错
He's right.
就... 就在这里面
It's, uh... it's in here.
就... 就在我这
It's, um... I have it.
就... 就在...
It's, um... it's, uh...
就... 就在这里头 在手机外壳里
It's... It's right here. It's... It's in the phone case.
嘿!
Hey!
联邦调查局
FBI.
简直太绝了
Oh, that was incredible.
但不许你再这么做
But don't do anything like that again.
这我可没法打包票
I don't know if I can promise that.
这边抓到两个人
All right, we got two men down.
又是在精英调查小组稀松平常的一天
Another typical day at White Collar.
终于圆了我最惦念的梦想
Well, I fulfilled one of my fondest dreams.
- 哦 是什么?  - 与你共事
- Yeah, what's that?  - Working with you.
- 喔  - 很有趣
- Aw.  - It was fun.
在匡蒂科的时候咱们确实对此谈了不少
We did talk about that at Quantico a lot.
非常符合期望
It lived up to expectations.
可你那时有过更宏伟的梦想
But you had bigger dreams back then.
去华盛顿
Washington.
马上?
Soon?
一旦我把这里的琐事处理完
Once I've tied up all the loose ends here.
是啊
Yeah.
我不能随便找个人来监管Neal
I can't just bring anyone in to be Neal's handler.
我得确保那个人能够胜任
I gotta make sure they're up to the task.
- Peter  - 怎么?
- Peter.  - What?
琐事是永远没个头的
There'll always be loose ends.
也是啊
Yeah.
还有件事得请你帮忙解答
Yeah, and there's one you might be able to help me with.
是件很久以前的事
Uh, this one is a cold case
困扰了我20年了
that has been gnawing at me for 20 years.
为什么选加州?
Why California?
你是班里的尖子生
You were top in our class.
你其实想选哪里都可以的
You could have had any assignment you wanted.
我选了啊
I took an assignment.
西海岸首位女性特别督查组成员
First female SSG agent on the west coast.
- 我怎么拒绝得了?  - 我也不会拦你
- How could I turn that down?  - I wouldn't have stopped you.
你一直想来纽约
You wanted New York.
华盛顿特区 那是你的梦想
D.C. That was your dream.
你跑了
You ran.
你也没追过来啊
You didn't chase after me.
那样你只会跑得更快
You would have just run faster.
说得对 我的确会这样
You're right. I would have.
至少这样我们都能记住匡蒂科
At least this way we can remember Quantico
美好的一面
as the beautiful thing it was.
这样挺好
Let's do that.
你接下来去哪?
Where you headed?
去迈阿密 下一个案子
Off to Miami. Another case.
我希望再有个案子能让你再来纽约一趟
Well, I hope another case brings you to New York again.
或许到时候我能带着我的那位El过来
Yeah, maybe I'll bring my El with me.
- 男版的El  - 能找到便是万幸
- Male edition.  - Good luck finding one.
她的确是万里挑一
She's one in a million.
别害怕跟她坦白 Peter
Don't be afraid to talk to her, Peter.
任何事情都是
About anything.
我本应早些跟你说这些的
I should have talked to you about this a long time ago,
但我无法将他从我脑中挥去
but I can't stop thinking about him.
我无法摆脱的想法是 要是我没当上特别探员主管
I can't shake the feeling that if I hadn't become ASAC
他也不会死
he'd still be alive.
相信我 好吗?
Just trust me, okay?
- 我能睁眼吗?  - 不许
- Can I open my eyes?  - No, you can't.
下来... 有台阶
Step down... Curb. Curb. Curb.
好了
There you go.
台阶没那么高啦
It's not that big of a curb.
我不喜欢惊喜 一般没什么好事
I don't like surprises. They never turn out good.
好了 我们快到了
All right, we're almost there.
你知道吗
You know, you should know that
蒙着眼睛走在纽约的街头
walking the streets of New York blind
简直是梦魇重现啊
is a recurring nightmare of mine.
可以睁眼了
You can open your eyes.
是法典里画的那扇窗
It's the window from the codex.
你怎么找到的?
How did you ever find it?
Gruetzner探员动用了黑道上认识的人
Agent Gruetzner used some of his underworld contacts.
美极了
It's beautiful.
一点也不专业
Not professional.
的确
No.
一点也不
Not professional at all.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 伊娃 翠西打酱油 噹噹 爱鼠影 捞小盐
校对: 爱鼠影